<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Anno regni Gulielmi III. Regis Angliæ, Scotiæ, Franciæ &amp; Hiberniæ, septimo &amp; octavo. At the parliament begun at Westminster the two and twentieth day of November, anno Dom. 1695 In the seventh year of the reign of our sovereign lord William the third, by the grace of God, of England, Scotland, France and Ireland, King, Defender of the Faith, &amp;c.</title>
            <title>Public General Acts. 1695-1696  7 &amp; 8 Gul.III.c.32</title>
            <author>England and Wales.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1696</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 25 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 7 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A82383</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E1033D</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R232779</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99900235</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99900235</idno>
            <idno type="VID">137680</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A82383)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 137680)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2555:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Anno regni Gulielmi III. Regis Angliæ, Scotiæ, Franciæ &amp; Hiberniæ, septimo &amp; octavo. At the parliament begun at Westminster the two and twentieth day of November, anno Dom. 1695 In the seventh year of the reign of our sovereign lord William the third, by the grace of God, of England, Scotland, France and Ireland, King, Defender of the Faith, &amp;c.</title>
                  <title>Public General Acts. 1695-1696  7 &amp; 8 Gul.III.c.32</title>
                  <author>England and Wales.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>12 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by Charles Bill, and the executrix of Thomas Newcomb deceas'd, printers to the Kings most excellent Majesty,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCXCVI. [1696]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title on p.3.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Public General Acts --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Hospitals --  England --  Bristol --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Almshouses --  England --  Bristol --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-10</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-09</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-09</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:137680:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>Anno Regni GULIELMI III. REGIS Angliae, Scotiae, Franciae &amp; Hiberniae, <hi>Septimo &amp; Octavo.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>At the Parliament begun at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the Two and twentieth Day of <hi>November, Anno Dom.</hi> 1695. In the Seventh Year of the Reign of our Sovereign Lord <hi>WILLIAM</hi> the Third, by the Grace of God, of <hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> King, Defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <figure>
               <head>W R</head>
               <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
               <q>DIEV ET MON DOIT</q>
               <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>Charles Bill,</hi> and the Executrix of <hi>Thomas Newcomb</hi> deceas'd, Printers to the Kings moſt Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent Majeſty. M DC XCVI.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:137680:2"/>
            <head>Anno Septimo &amp; Octavo Gulielmi III. Regis.</head>
            <head type="sub">An Act for Erecting of Hoſpitals and Work<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſes within the City of <hi>Briſtoll,</hi> for the bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Employing and Maintaining the Poor thereof.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas it is found by Experience, That the Poor in the City of <hi>Briſtoll</hi> do daily multiply, and Idleneſs and Debauchery amongſt the meaner Sort doth greatly Increaſe, for want of Work-houſes to ſet them to Work, and a ſufficient Authority to Compel them thereto, as well to the Charge of the Inhabitants and Grief of the Charitable and Honeſt Citizens of the ſaid City, as the great Diſtreſs of the Poor themſelves; for which ſufficient Redreſs hath not yet beén Provided: For Remedy whereof, Be it Enacted by the Kings moſt Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellent Majeſty, by and with the Advice and Conſent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons in Parliament Aſſembled, and by the Authority of the ſame, That from and after the Twelfth Day of <hi>May,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of our Lord, One thouſand ſix hundred ninety and ſix, there be, and ſhall be a Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration to continue for ever, within the ſaid City of <hi>Briſtoll,</hi> and the County thereof, conſiſting of the ſeveral Perſons herein after mentioned (that is to ſay) of the Mayor and Aldermen for the time being, and of Eight and forty other Perſons, to be Choſen out of the Honeſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:137680:3"/>and Diſcreéteſt Inhabitants of the ſaid City and County, by the Eleven Wards in the ſaid City, and the Caſtle Precincts there, which to all Intents and Purpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, ſhall be from henceforth for ever a Ward within the ſaid City (that is to ſay) Four out of each Ward, and of ſuch other Charitable Perſons as ſhall be Elected and Conſtituted Guardiaus of the Poor of the ſaid City, in manner as is herein after Expreſſed: And the ſaid Firſt Eight and forty Perſons ſhall be Elected at a Court for that Purpoſe to be held within each Ward, by the Alderman of the ſame, or his Deputy, by the Votes of the Inhabitants of ſuch Ward, Paying One Peny <hi>per</hi> Weék, or more, in his own Right, for and towards the Relief of the Poor of the ſaid City, or of the major Part of them then preſent.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Eight and forty Perſons ſhall be choſen in manner, as aforeſaid, the ſaid Twelfth day of <hi>May</hi> next following, and ſhall continue in their Office until o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers ſhall be Elected in their Rooms, according to the direction herein after mentioned; And in caſe any of the ſaid Perſons ſo Elected, or any other Perſon Elected in their Room, ſhall, after their reſpective Elections, hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen to die, That then it ſhall and may be Lawful, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>, and for the Alderman of the Ward, for which ſuch Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſo Dying was Elected, or his Deputy, at a Court to be held within the ſaid Ward for that purpoſe, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſpace of Ten days next after the Death of ſuch Perſons, to Elect others in their place, in manner, as aforeſaid; which Court and Election, ſuch Alderman or his Deputy is, and are hereby required to Hold and Make: Which ſaid Mayor and Aldermen, and Forty eight Perſons, and ſuch other Charitable Perſons ſo E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lected and Conſtituted for the time being, ſhall be called Guardians of the Poor of the City of <hi>Briſtoll.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And to the intent that the ſaid Guardians ſo Elected out of the ſaid Wards, may have perpetual Succeſſion, Be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid reſpective Aldermen for the time being, or their reſpective Deputies, ſhall and may, and are hereby re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired, on the Firſt <hi>Thurſday</hi> in <hi>April,</hi> in every Second Year, from henceforth, to hold a Court in their reſpective Wards, and then and there, by the Votes of the Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants of ſuch Ward, ſo qualified, as aforeſaid, or of the
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:137680:3"/>Majority of them then preſent, to Elect and Chooſe Two of the Honeſteſt and Diſcreéteſt Perſons out of the ſaid Inhabitants of the ſaid City, to be Guardians of the Poor of the ſaid City for the ſaid Ward; which ſaid Two Perſons, ſo Elected, ſhall be Guardians, and ſhall Succeéd the Two Perſous before that time firſt Elected, and then being Guardians for the ſaid Ward; and the ſaid Two Perſons ſo firſt Elected, ſhall immediately, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on ſuch Election, and Notice thereof given to them ceaſe to be Guardians.</p>
            <p>And be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Mayor, Aldermen, Eight and forty Perſons, and ſuch other Charitable Perſons Elected and Conſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuted, as is herein mentioned and expreſſed, for the time being, ſhall for ever hereafter in Name and Fact, be One Body Politick and Corporate in Law, to all Intents and Purpoſes, and ſhall have a perpetual Succeſſion, and be called by the Name of the Governour, Deputy Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, Aſſiſtants and Guardians of the Poor in the ſaid City of <hi>Briſtoll;</hi> And that they ſhall be Enabled to Plead and Sue, and to be Sued and Impleaded by that Name, in all Courts and Places of Iudicature within this Kingdom; and by that Name ſhall and may, without Licence in Mortmain, Purchaſe, Take, or Receive any Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments, of the Gift, Ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>enation or Demiſe, of any Perſon or Perſons, who are hereby, without further Licence, Enabled to Transfer the ſame, and any Goods and Chattels whatſoever, for the Vſe and Benefit of the Corporation aforeſaid. And for the better Governing of the ſaid Corporation, the ſaid Mayor, Aldermen, and Eight and forty Perſons, or the Majority of them, ſhall have, and hereby have Authority, to meet on the Nineteenth Day of <hi>May</hi> next following, in St. <hi>Georges Chappel</hi> in the ſaid City, or in ſome other convenient Place there, and ſhall on that Day, or any other Day or Time, that to them ſhall ſeem convenient, Elect and Conſtitute out of, and from amongſt them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, the ſeveral Officers following (that is to ſay) One Governour, One Deputy Governour, One Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurer, and Twelve Aſſiſtants, to continue in the ſaid Office for One Year, and no longer; And from thence<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forth the ſaid Governour, Deputy Governour, Aſſiſtants, Treaſurer, and other Officers, ſhall yearly, and every Year, by the ſaid Mayor, Aldermen, Forty eight Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:137680:4"/>and ſuch other Charitable Perſons as ſhall be Elected and Conſtituted, as is herein mentioned and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed, or the Majority of them, be Elected and Conſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted out of, and from amongſt themſelves, on the Second <hi>Thurſday</hi> in the Month of <hi>April,</hi> or any other Day or Time, as they ſhall think convenient to continue in their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Offices, for One Year, and no longer; And the ſaid Mayor, Aldermen, and Forty eight Perſons, and ſuch other Charitable Perſons that ſhall be Elected and Conſtituted, as is herein mentioned and expreſſed, for the time being, or the Majority of them<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ſhall have Power, in caſe of the Death of any ſuch Officer ſo Elected and Conſtituted, before their ſaid Year expired, to Elect and Conſtitute others in their Room, to hold the ſaid Office for the Remainder of the ſaid Year, and ſhall have Power and Authority at any time or times, for juſt Cauſe, to remove, diſplace and put out any ſuch Officer out of his ſaid Office, and to Elect and Conſtitute another in his room.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Governour, or in his Default, the ſaid Deputy Governour, or in both their Defaults, Six of the ſaid Aſſiſtants for the time being, ſhall have, and hereby have Power and Authority, and are hereby En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyned and Required from time to time, upon the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond <hi>Thurſday</hi> in every Second Month in every Year, accounting <hi>January</hi> for the Firſt Mouth, to hold and keép a Court or Aſſembly of the ſaid Corporation within the ſaid City of <hi>Briſtoll</hi> of One and twenty of the ſaid Guardians at leaſt, on the days and time, and in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, and for the ends in this Act mentioned; (that is to ſay) The ſaid Governour ſhall hold the ſaid Court or Aſſembly betweén the hours of One and Two in the Afternoon; and in his Default, the ſaid Deputy Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, or any Six of the ſaid Aſſiſtants, ſhall, after the hour of Two, hold the ſame; And alſo, the ſaid Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernour for the time being, ſhall have, and hereby hath Power and Authority, at any ſuch other time or times as to him ſhall ſeém meet, to Summon, Aſſemble and Hold a Court or Aſſembly of the ſaid Corporation upon Two days Notice or Warning at the leaſt to be given of ſuch Court or Aſiembly to be held; And in caſe any Twenty of the ſaid Guardians upon any Emergeney, ſignifying it under their Hands to the Goveruour for the
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:137680:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>time being, That it is their Deſire that an Extraordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Court or Aſſembly of the ſaid Corporation may he Called and Held, the ſaid Governour ſhall be Bound, and is hereby Enjoyned and Required to Call and Hold ſuch Court or Aſſembly at ſuch time as the ſaid Twenty Guardians ſhall ſo deſire; and on his Refuſal, the ſaid Deputy Governour for the time being on ſuch ſignificati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, ſhall be Bound, and is hereby likewiſe Enjoyned and Required to Call and Hold the ſaid Court or Aſſembly, and on his Refuſal, any Six of the ſaid Aſſiſtants ſhall have, and hereby have Authority to Call and Hold the ſaid Court or Aſſembly; at all which Courts or Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blies all and every Member and Members of the ſaid Corporation for the time being, are hereby Enjoyned to appear and be preſent, and not to depart from the ſame without the Licence of the ſaid Court or Aſſembly, on pain to Forfeit ſuch reaſonable Sum and Sums of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, not exceéding Five Shillings, to the Vſe of the ſaid Corporation, as by the ſaid Court or Aſſembly, or any ſucceéding Court or Aſſembly ſhall be Aſſeſſed upon them, unleſs they can ſhew ſome reaſonable Excuſe to be allowed of by the ſaid Court or Aſſembly; And the ſaid Court or Aſſembly are hereby Impowered to Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon to appear before them any of the Inhabitants of the ſaid City to anſwer to Matters relating to the ſaid Corporation, who are hereby Required to appear upon ſuch Summons, and anſwer ſuch Queſtions, on For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture, to the Vſe of the ſaid Corporation, of a Sum not exceéding Two ſhillings and Six pence for every Default, to be Levied as is herein after Directed.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted, by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Corporation, at the ſaid Court or Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly, ſhall have, and hereby have Power and Authority from time to time to make and appoint a Common Seal or Seals for the Vſe of the ſaid Corporation, and to Make and Ordain By-Laws, Rules and Ordinances for and concerning the better Governing the ſaid Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, and the Poor of the ſaid City, and ſhall have, and have hereby Power to Purchaſe, Buy or Exect an Hoſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal or Hoſpitals, Work houſe or Work houſes, Houſe or Houſes of Correction, and to provide what other Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſaries they ſhall think convenient for the Seeting to Work the Poor of the ſaid City, of what Sex or Age ſoever they be, and ſhall have, and hereby have Power
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:137680:5"/>and Authority to Compel ſuch Idle or Poor People begging or ſeéking Relief, who do not betake themſelves to ſome lawful Imployments, and ſuch other Poor who do or ſhall hereafter Receive Alms of the reſpective Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhes or Places where they Inhabit or Seék the ſame, or by any of the Laws now in Force ought to be Main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained or Provided for by any Pariſh or Place within the ſaid City, to Dwell and Inhabit in ſuch Hoſpital or Hoſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pitals, Work houſe or Work houſes, and to do ſuch Work as they ſhall think them Able and Fit for; and to detain and keép in the Service of the ſaid Corporation, until the Age of Sixteén Years, any Poor Child or Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of the ſaid City, left to be Maintained by the ſaid City, or any Pariſh or Place in the ſame, or begging or ſeéking Relief, or which by any of the Laws now in Force ought to be Maintained and Provided for by any Pariſh or Place within the ſaid City, or the Child or Children of any other Perſon or Perſons that are or ſhall be willing or deſirous to place or put their Child or Children in ſuch Hoſpital or Hoſpitals, until their ſaid Age of Sixteén Years; and after they ſhall have at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained their ſaid Age of Sixteén Years or ſooner, the ſaid Corporation, by Indenture, ſhall have Power to Bind and put Forth ſuch Child or Children Apprentices, to any Honeſt Perſon or Perſons within the Kingdom of <hi>England</hi> for any Number of Years, not exceéding Seven Years, as they ſhall think convenient; which Indenture ſhall be binding to ſuch Child or Children.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Court or Aſſembly ſo Conſtituted, as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, ſhall have, and hereby have power to inflict ſuch reaſonable Correction and Puniſhment, on any Poor Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or Perſons within the ſaid Hoſpital or Hoſpitals, Work houſe or Work houſes, Houſe or Houſes of Correcti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, that ſhall not conform to ſuch Rules, Orders and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinances ſo made, as aforeſaid, or miſbehave themſelves in the ſame; And that the ſaid Court or Aſſembly ſo Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtituted, as aforeſaid, ſhall have, and hereby have Power to appoint a Committee to conſiſt of One and twenty of the Guardians at the leaſt, who, or any five of them<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> of which Two ſhall be Aſſiſtants, ſhall from time to time, or at any time until the next Court, have Power to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flict ſuch reaſonable Correction and Puniſhment, as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, on any ſuch Poor Perſon or Perſons offencing, as aforeſaid.</p>
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:137680:5"/>
            <p>And for the better Carrying on ſo Pious and Chari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table a Week, Be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That it ſhall and may be Lawful for the ſaid Corporati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, in their ſaid Courts or Aſſemblies, from time to time, to ſet down and aſcertain what Sum or Sums of Money ſhall be neédful for the Building and Erecting of ſuch Hoſpitals, Work houſes, or Houſes of Correction, ſo that the ſame do not exceéd the Sum of Five thouſand Pounds, to be raiſed within the ſpace of Threé Years, or any lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger time, as to them ſhall ſeém meét, by ſuch Quarterly or other Payments, as they in their diſcretion ſhall think fit; And alſo from time to time, to Set down and Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>certain what Weékly, Monthly, or other Sums, ſhall be neédful for the maintenance of the Poor in the ſaid Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpital or Hoſpitals, Work-houſe or Work-houſes, Houſe or Houſes of Correction, or within the Care of the ſaid Corporation, ſo that the ſame do not exceéd what hath beén Paid in the ſaid City towards the maintenance of the Poor thereof, in any one of the Threé laſt Years; And ſhall and may under their Common Seal, certify the ſame unto the Mayor and Aldermen of the ſaid City for the time being; which ſaid Mayor and any Two of the Aldermen, or any Five of the ſaid Aldermen without the Mayor, may, and are hereby Required from time to time, to cauſe the ſame to be Raiſed and Levied by Tax<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ation of every Inhabitant, and of all Lands, Houſes, Tythes impropriate, Appropriation of Tythes, and all Stocks and Eſtates in the ſaid City and County of the ſame, in equal proportion, according to their reſpective Worth and Values: And in order thereunto, the ſaid Mayor and any Two of the ſaid Aldermen, or any Five of the ſaid Aldermen without the Mayor, ſhall have Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, and are hereby Required indifferently, to proportion out the ſaid Sum and Sums upon each Pariſh and Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cinct within the ſaid City, and by their Warrants under their Hands and Seals, to Authorize and Require the Churchwardens and Overſeérs of the Poor of each re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Pariſh and Precinct, to Aſſeſs the ſame reſpective<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly; And after ſuch Aſſeſſment made, by like Warrant under their Hands and Seals, to Authorize the ſaid re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Churchwardens and Overſeérs, to Demand, Gather and Receive the ſame, and for Non-payment thereof (being Lawfully Demanded) to Levy the ſame by Diſtreſs and Sale of the Goods of the Offender, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoring
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:137680:6"/>the Surpluſage to the Party ſo Diſtrained; And if no Diſtreſs can be found, then it ſhall and may be Lawful, to, and for the ſaid Mayor and any Two of the Aldermen, or any Five of the ſaid Aldermen without the Mayor, to commit ſuch Offender to Priſon, there to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main without Bail or Mainprize, till the ſame ſhall be Paid: And after the ſame ſhall be Received, to Pay the ſame unto the Treaſurer of the ſaid Corporation for the time being. Provided always, That if any Perſon or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, Pariſh or Precinct, find him or themſelves to be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>equally Taxed or Aſſeſſed, he or they may Appeal to the Iuſtices of the Peace of the ſaid City and County, at their next General Quarter Seſſions after ſuch Aſſeſſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment made and demanded, who ſhall and hereby have full Power and Authority, to take and make a final Order therein.</p>
            <p>And for the Incouragement of ſuch as ſhall be Bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factors to ſo good a Deſign, Be it Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforeſaid, That if any Man Charitably Diſpoſed, ſhall give One hundred Pounds, or more, towards carry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing on the ſaid Work, It ſhall and may be Lawful for the ſaid Corporation, at a Court, where there ſhall be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Three and thirty of the ſaid Guardians at the leaſt, to Elect and Conſtitute ſuch Charitable Perſon to be a Guardian of the Poor of the ſaid City, and to continue in the ſaid Office, as long as to the ſaid Corporation ſhall ſeém meét.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Corporation ſhall have the Care of, and Provide for the Maintenance of all the Poor of the ſaid City, of what Age or Kind ſoever they be, except ſuch as ſhall be otherwiſe ſufficiently Provided for, by the Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritable Gifts of other Perſons, or in Hoſpitals or Alms<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſes within the ſaid City already Erected; And in order thereunto ſhall have full Power to Examine, Search and See what Poor Perſons there are come into, Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biting or Reſiding within the ſaid City, or any Part there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of; And ſhall have Power to Apprehend, or cauſe to be Apprehended, any Rogues, Vagrants, Sturdy Beggars, or Idle or Diſorderly Perſons within the ſaid City and the County thereof, and to cauſe them to be kept and ſet to Work in the ſaid Work-houſes, Hoſpitals or Houſes of Correction, for the Space of Three Years.</p>
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:137680:6"/>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That this Act, or any thing herein contained, ſhall not any ways extend to give the ſaid Corporation any Power or Authority over any Almſhouſe, or Hoſpital, or any other Charitable Gift or Vſe, within the ſaid City already Given, Settled or Erected, but that the ſame ſhall be wholly exempted therefrom, any thing herein to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Corporation in their ſaid Court or Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly, ſhall have hereby Power to Chooſe and Entertain all ſuch other Officers as ſhall be neédful to be Employed in and about the Premiſſes, and them, or any of them, from time to time, to remove, as they ſhall ſeé Cauſe; and upon the Death or Removal of them, or any of them, to chooſe others in their place, and to make and give ſuch reaſonable Allowances to them, or any of them, out of the Stock or Revenue belonging to the ſaid Corporation or Hoſpitals, as they ſhall think fit.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That no Officer or Officers, who ſhall be Elected, Choſen, Appointed or Employed, in the Execution of, or by Virtue of this Act, or any of the Powers or Authorities thereby given, ſhall be liable for, or by reaſon of ſuch Office or Execution, to any of the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalties mentioned in an Act made the Five and twentieth Year of the Reign of King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, for the preventing the Dangers which may happen from Popiſh Recuſants.</p>
            <p>And it is further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That the ſaid Treaſurer for the time being, and all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Officers belonging to the ſaid Corporation, Hoſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tals, Work-houſes, or Houſes of Correction, ſhall from time to time, before ſuch Perſon or Perſons as the ſaid Corporation ſhall thereto appoint, Account for ſuch Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys, Stock, and other Things belonging to the ſaid Corporation, Hoſpitals, Work-houſes, or Houſes of Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection, as ſhall come to their reſpective Hands, or be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der their reſpective Care, upon every reaſonable warning and notice thereof, by the ſaid Corporation to them re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpectively given; And on their Neglect or Refuſal to Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count, as aforeſaid, ſhall or may be by the ſaid Mayor, or any Two of the ſaid Aldermen, Committed to the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Goal for the ſaid City and County of <hi>Briſtoll,</hi> there to
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:137680:7"/>Remain without Bail or Mainprize, until they ſhall be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come Conformable, and account, as aforeſaid; And if upon ſuch Account there ſhall appear any thing to be in their Hands belonging to the ſaid Corporation, Hoſpitals, Work houſes, or Houſes of Correction, they ſhall Pay and Deliver the ſame, as the ſaid Corporation ſhall Direct, or Give ſuch Security for the ſame, as the ſaid Corporation ſhall approve of, on pain to Forfeit Double the Value thereof, to be Recovered by the ſaid Corporation by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information, in which no Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tection, Eſſoign or Wager of Law, or any more than One Imparlance ſhall be admitted or allowed.</p>
            <p>And it is further Enacted, That all other Pains, Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalties and Forfeitures by this Act appointed, ſhall be Levied by Diſtreſs and Sale of the Offenders Goods, by Warrant under the Hand and Seal of the ſaid Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurer for the time being, Reſtoring to the Offender the Overplus.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, That if any Perſon or Perſons ſhall be Sued for any Matter or Thing which he ſhall do in Execution of this Act, he may Plead the General Iſſue, and give the Special Matter in Evidence; And if the Verdict ſhall Paſs for the Defendant, or the Plaintiff ſhall be Nouſuited or Diſcontinue his Suit, the Defendant ſhall Recover his Treble Coſts. And this Act ſhall be Taken and be Allowed in all Courts within this Kingdom as a Publick Act; And all Iudges and Iuſtices are hereby Required, as ſuch, to take notice thereof, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out ſpecially Pleading the ſame; And all Mayors, Iu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices, Sheriffs, Bayliffs, Conſtables, and all other Officers and Miniſters of Iuſtice, are hereby Required to be Aiding and Aſſiſting to the ſaid Corporation, and to all ſuch Officers as ſhall be Employed by them, or any of them, in the Execution of this Act, or any of the Powers or Authorities hereby given.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
